Sudarshan.S

Senior 3D Game | XR Engineer | Lead

16,Deivanayagam St, Nungambakkam, Chennai,Tn,India-600034 (+91) 8838750579 sudars.1989@gmail.com

PROFILE

3D Software Developer having Eleven years of full life cycle development experience including planning and assessment, requirements gathering, features design & functionality development, coding, testing, QA, implementation, product & infrastructure enhancements and maintenance. An expert in object-oriented design and analysis with a history of building unique, original products & solutions through intuitive problem-solving and creativity. Experienced in developing desktop, web, mobile, kinect, Jio Glass, Jio Stb and oculusVR applications.

EXPERIENCE

Byjus, Bengaluru — *Technical Lead*

4 JUNE 2022 - Present.

Embibe, Bengaluru — Senior Unity 3D Developer

11 MARCH 2020 -28 MAY 2022 (28/05/2022).

Nanlogical Consultancy Services, Chennai — Senior Software Engineer

JULY 2016 - MARCH 2020

Spatika Digital Solutions, Chennai — *Software Engineer*

MARCH 2012 - JULY 2016

EDUCATION

Icat Design and Media College, Chennai — *PGDM Game Development*

APRIL 2011 - APRIL 2012

Vel Tech Engineering College, Chennai — BE Computer Science

SEPTEMBER 2006 - MAY 2010

SKILLS

Languages: C#,C++,Javascript and Python.

Frameworks: Unity3D,Unreal Engine 4, Ogre3D, OpenCV, Kinect, ReactNative and Flask.

Concepts: OOA/OOD, DOD, Concurrency, AI, Agile and Networking.

Softwares:Ms Tools, Xcode, Git, Jira and Atlassian Tools.

AWARDS

Tech Enthusiast: My work on Jio Glass and Jio Stb won me this award at Embibe.

Clients Hero: Clients chose me for my contribution at Nanlogical.

Top Newbie: Came Top as a fresher at Spatika.

Best Project: The JigSaw puzzle game that I created at Icat won me this.

LANGUAGES

English and Tamil

PROJECTS

Disney Byju's Early Learning - Multi Platform - *BYJUS* **-** JUNE2022 - PRESENT Virtual Learning for Pre-k To Grade 3.

Virtual Lab Experiments - Multi Platform - *Embibe* **-** MARCH 2021 - MAY 2022 Laboratory Simulation for School and College Students using Unity3d.

Coboo Editor & Player - Multi Platform - *Embibe* **-** MARCH 2020 - FEBUARY 2021 Simulation Editor and Player built using Unity3d.

Military Training - Desktop/VR - Ncs - JULY 2016 - MARCH 2020

Mission Planner and Execution Training system for pilots, drivers and operators built using Unity3d.

VersaCell Simulation - Multi Platform — Siemens - JANUARY 2016 - JULY 2016Virtual Training For VersaCell System built using Unity3d.

Procleix Tigris Simulation - Multi Platform — *Grifols* - JULY 2015 - DECEMBER 2015 Virtual Training For Procleix Tigris System built using Unreal Engine 4.

Mobile Adjustor - Multi Platform — *Cognizant* - FEBRUARY 2015 - JULY 2015 Built for Automobile Insurance Training built using Unity3d Engine.

Surfboard Customization – Multi Platform — *Bumo3dr* – SEPTEMBER 2014 - JANUARY 2015 Built to use Kinect to customize surfboards using Ogre3d Engine.

HCS Laboratory Inspection - Multi Platform — Siemens - MAY 2014 - SEPTEMBER 2014Readings Taker and report generation tool for all Siemens laboratory automation .

Laboratory Automation - Multi Platform — OrthoClinical Diagnostics - NOVEMBER 2013 - APRIL 2014 3D Virtual Lab Builder Tool developed on Unreal Engine 4.

Networked Car Assembly - Ipad — *Bumo3dr* **-** JULY 2013 - OCTOBER 2013 Automobile Teaching Platform developed on Unity3D Engine.

Networked Car Assembly - Desktop — *Bumo3dr* - JANUARY 2013 - JUNE 2013 Automobile Teaching Platform developed on Ogre3D Engine.

Panther Simulation - Desktop — *Grifols* **-** JUNE 2012 - DECEMBER 2012 Training Simulation developed on Ogre3D Engine.